Welcome to the frontline.
Civil War is a war, action, drama film directed by Alex Garland.
In the near future, a group of war journalists attempt to survive while reporting
the truth as the United States stands on the brink of civil war.
Lee, played by Kirsten Dunst.
Joel, played by Wagner Moura.
Jessie, played by Cailee Spaeny.
Sammy, played by Stephen McKinley Henderson.
Tony, played by Nelson Lee.
President, played by Nick Offerman.
Civil War is a 2024 dystopian action thriller film written and directed by Alex Garland, starring Kirsten
Dunst, Wagner Moura, Cailee Spaeny, Stephen McKinley Henderson, Sonoya Mizuno, and Nick Offerman.
Set during a civil war fought across the United States between a despotic federal government and secessionist movements, the plot follows a group of war
journalists traveling from New York City to Washington, D.C., to interview the President of the United States before rebels take the capital city.
Principal photography began in Atlanta, Georgia, in 2022, with
production moving to London later in the year.
Civil War premiered at South by Southwest on March 14, 2024, and was theatrically released in the United
States by A24 and in the United Kingdom by Entertainment Film Distributors on April 12, 2024.
With a budget of $50 million, Civil War was A24's
most expensive film at the time.
The film grossed over $127.3 million worldwide, becoming A24's
second-highest-grossing film, and received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of sniper, new york city, race
against time, washington dc, usa, the white house.
The tone is emotional.